<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>HUGO on markkerry.github.io</title><link>https://markkerry.github.io/tags/hugo/</link><description>Recent content in HUGO on markkerry.github.io</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2021 12:13:43 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://markkerry.github.io/tags/hugo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>HUGO Static Site Hosted on GitHub Pages - Part 1: Intro</title><link>https://markkerry.github.io/posts/hugo-and-github-pages-part1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2021 12:13:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://markkerry.github.io/posts/hugo-and-github-pages-part1/</guid><description>The following series of posts will walk through the process I used to create and build this HUGO site, hosted in GitHub Pages. Everything required in the following posts is free. HUGO/templates, GitHub Pages, GitHub Actions is all free to use.
What is HUGO? HUGO is an open source static site generator written in GO. I chose HUGO because it looked simple to get started, all posts are written in markdown, and was compatible with GitHub pages.</description></item><item><title>HUGO Static Site Hosted on GitHub Pages - Part 2: Create the Site</title><link>https://markkerry.github.io/posts/hugo-and-github-pages-part2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2021 12:11:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://markkerry.github.io/posts/hugo-and-github-pages-part2/</guid><description>Assuming at this stage you have installed all the prerequisite apps required in Part 1 to get started with HUGO: Git, GitHub Desktop, and HUGO.
The Official HUGO getting started docs are a great resource to read through and recommend you get started there if you are having any trouble following the below.
Create the Site Browse to your local directory where you want to keep the site&amp;rsquo;s source files, and enter the following commands to create the site (change markkerry to your GitHub username).</description></item><item><title>HUGO Static Site Hosted on GitHub Pages - Part 3: Build and Deploy</title><link>https://markkerry.github.io/posts/hugo-and-github-pages-part3/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2021 12:09:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://markkerry.github.io/posts/hugo-and-github-pages-part3/</guid><description>Now that we&amp;rsquo;ve created our site and first post, we can start creating the repos to build, deploy and host the static site.
Create the Two GitHub Repositories Browse to GitHub and create two new repos. More info on how to do this can be found here
The two repos will be named as follows:
username-hugo (mine is markkerry-hugo) username.github.io (mine is markkerry.github.io) The username-hugo repo is where we are going to commit our site to.</description></item></channel></rss>