<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Azure on markkerry.github.io</title><link>https://markkerry.github.io/tags/azure/</link><description>Recent content in Azure on markkerry.github.io</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Jul 2021 12:55:22 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://markkerry.github.io/tags/azure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Azure ARM Templates - Part 3: Deployment</title><link>https://markkerry.github.io/posts/azure-arm-templates-part-3-deployment/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jul 2021 12:55:22 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://markkerry.github.io/posts/azure-arm-templates-part-3-deployment/</guid><description>In the third and final post of this series I&amp;rsquo;ll quickly cover the process to deploy the ARM template with PowerShell
Deploy Open PowerShell and change directory to the location of your ARM template and parameter files. Then complete the following commands to connect to Azure and create a Resource Group to deploy the resources to:
# Import the Azure Az PowerShell Module Import-Module -Name Az # Connect to Azure and authenticate Connect-AzAccount # Create the Resource Group New-AzResourceGroup -Name &amp;#34;rg-eu-vm&amp;#34; -Location &amp;#34;westeurope&amp;#34; Once the Resource Group has been created it&amp;rsquo;s time to deploy the resources using the New-AzResourceGroupDeployment cmdlet.</description></item><item><title>Azure ARM Templates - Part 2: Testing</title><link>https://markkerry.github.io/posts/azure-arm-templates-part-2-testing/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 15:50:08 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://markkerry.github.io/posts/azure-arm-templates-part-2-testing/</guid><description>Following on from authoring the Azure ARM Templates - Part 1: Development post, in this one I will cover testing the ARM template.
Two potential ways to test the ARM templates is by manually building a Pester test, and another is by using Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s Azure Resource Manager Template Toolkit (arm-ttk) module.
You can run local tests against ARM templates using PowerShell - which I will demonstrate in the post - but most commonly template testing and validating is used during a CI pipeline.</description></item><item><title>Azure ARM Templates - Part 1: Development</title><link>https://markkerry.github.io/posts/azure-arm-templates-part-1-development/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 13:05:17 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://markkerry.github.io/posts/azure-arm-templates-part-1-development/</guid><description>In the first of this three part series of posts, I will breakdown the components of an Azure ARM template, and the tools used to develop one. Then in part two I will cover testing an ARM template. And finally in part three, I will cover deploying the resources in the ARM template to Azure.
The ARM template will consist of the following resources:
Windows VM Network Interface Public IP Virtual Network Network Security Group Storage Account Getting Started Before looking at Bicep, Terraform or Pulumi, I think it&amp;rsquo;s important to get to know the process of developing Azure ARM templates from scratch.</description></item><item><title>Serverless LAPS Azure Function and Proactive Remediation</title><link>https://markkerry.github.io/posts/serverless-laps-azure-function/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Apr 2021 11:04:45 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://markkerry.github.io/posts/serverless-laps-azure-function/</guid><description>Based on the great solution created by John Seerden with a little help creating and deploying Azure Functions by the Serverless on Azure YouTube channel.
All of the code in this post can be found in my GitHub repo
I am only posting a few differences here, such as creating the Azure resources using AZ CLI and creating/testing/deploying the function using the Azure Functions Core Tools CLI.
What is Serverless LAPS Local Admin Password Solution (LAPS) is a great solution from Microsoft to allow IT admins to automatically recycle local admin accounts on domain joined Windows machines.</description></item></channel></rss>