<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Azure on markkerry.github.io</title><link>https://markkerry.github.io/tags/azure/</link><description>Recent content in Azure on markkerry.github.io</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 13:05:17 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://markkerry.github.io/tags/azure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Azure ARM Templates - Part 1: Development</title><link>https://markkerry.github.io/posts/azure-arm-templates-part-1-development/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 13:05:17 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://markkerry.github.io/posts/azure-arm-templates-part-1-development/</guid><description>In the first of this three part series of posts, I will breakdown the components of an Azure ARM template, and the tools used to develop one. Then in part two I will cover testing an ARM template. And finally in part three, I will cover deploying the resources in the ARM template to Azure.
The ARM template will consist of the following resources:
Windows VM Network Interface Public IP Virtual Network Network Security Group Storage Account Getting Started Before looking at Bicep, Terraform or Pulumi, I think it&amp;rsquo;s important to get to know the process of developing Azure ARM templates from scratch.</description></item><item><title>Serverless LAPS Azure Function and Proactive Remediation</title><link>https://markkerry.github.io/posts/serverless-laps-azure-function/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Apr 2021 11:04:45 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://markkerry.github.io/posts/serverless-laps-azure-function/</guid><description>Based on the great solution created by John Seerden with a little help creating and deploying Azure Functions by the Serverless on Azure YouTube channel.
All of the code in this post can be found in my GitHub repo
I am only posting a few differences here, such as creating the Azure resources using AZ CLI and creating/testing/deploying the function using the Azure Functions Core Tools CLI.
What is Serverless LAPS Local Admin Password Solution (LAPS) is a great solution from Microsoft to allow IT admins to automatically recycle local admin accounts on domain joined Windows machines.</description></item></channel></rss>