<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Ansible on markkerry.github.io</title><link>https://markkerry.github.io/tags/ansible/</link><description>Recent content in Ansible on markkerry.github.io</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 09:29:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://markkerry.github.io/tags/ansible/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Configure Windows Server 2022 with Ansible</title><link>https://markkerry.github.io/posts/2022/04/windows-cis-with-ansible/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 09:29:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://markkerry.github.io/posts/2022/04/windows-cis-with-ansible/</guid><description>In a Windows Server environment which is not domain joined and where group policies are available to configure hosts, it is important to harden the server infrastructure against security vulnerabilities via other methods. In this post I will demonstrate applying the CIS security policies for Windows Server with Ansible. You can find all the configurations for this post on GitHub - ubuntu-config/ansible-win.
Since Ansible cannot be installed on Windows, I am using the same adminbox Ubuntu host which has Ansible installed already from the following posts:</description></item><item><title>Ansible Part 1: Setup and Configure on Ubuntu and VirtualBox</title><link>https://markkerry.github.io/posts/2022/04/ansible-part-1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2022 10:32:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://markkerry.github.io/posts/2022/04/ansible-part-1/</guid><description>This is part one in a three part Ansible series, which will demonstrate how you can get started learning Ansible. The complete list of posts in this series are:
Ansible Part 1: Setup and Configure on Ubuntu and VirtualBox (This post) Ansible Part 2: Playbooks Ansible Part 3: Variables, Vault and Roles All code in these posts can be found on GitHub - ubuntu-config/ansible
Getting Started I used the adminbox VM connected to the KubeNatNetwork (10.</description></item><item><title>Ansible Part 2: Playbooks</title><link>https://markkerry.github.io/posts/2022/04/ansible-part-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2022 10:31:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://markkerry.github.io/posts/2022/04/ansible-part-2/</guid><description>In this post I&amp;rsquo;ll be going over Ansible Playbooks. The complete list of posts in this series are:
Ansible Part 1: Setup and Configure on Ubuntu and VirtualBox Ansible Part 2: Playbooks (This post) Ansible Part 3: Variables, Vault and Roles All code in these posts can be found on GitHub - ubuntu-config/ansible
Playbooks Playbooks allow us to write ordered process and manage configurations in the form of yaml syntax. These can then be used to build out remote systems.</description></item><item><title>Ansible Part 3: Variables, Vault and Roles</title><link>https://markkerry.github.io/posts/2022/04/ansible-part-3/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2022 10:30:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://markkerry.github.io/posts/2022/04/ansible-part-3/</guid><description>In this post I&amp;rsquo;ll demonstrate using variables in your Ansible Playbooks, then go on to secret management using Ansible Vault, before finally completing the post covering Ansible Roles. The complete list of posts in this series are:
Ansible Part 1: Setup and Configure on Ubuntu and VirtualBox Ansible Part 2: Playbooks Ansible Part 3: Variables, Vault and Roles (This post) All code in these posts can be found on GitHub - ubuntu-config/ansible and GitHub - ubuntu-config/ansible-roles</description></item></channel></rss>